Hi, there.
你们好
I'll be your server for tonight.
今晚由我为你们服务
My name is Brian if you guys need anything.
我叫布莱恩  有任何需要尽管叫我
What's your name if we don't need anything?
如果我们没有任何需要该叫你什么
Patricia.
帕特丽夏
You're quick, Patricia!
反应很快嘛  帕特丽夏
Thanks. So, our specialty cocktail for tonight
谢谢  我们今晚的特别鸡尾酒是
is a basil-infused mojito.
罗勒莫吉托
Oh, yum! We'll take three.
不错  我们要三杯
Uh, no. That's okay. I'm good.
不用了  没关系  我不想喝酒
Come on, now. Join us for a specialty cocktail
拜托  跟我们一起在这特别的夜晚
- on our specialty evening. - Yeah.
-喝杯特别的鸡尾酒吧  -就是
- Three, please. - Okay.
-请给我们三杯  -好的
If you don't drink it, someone will.
你不喝的话  会有人喝的
Well, that Brian sure is a cutie, huh?
那个布莱恩真是个帅哥  是吧
I'd kill to have those lips. I mean on me.
我真想要那两片嘴唇  我是说在我身上
I mean I want his lips on my mouth.
我是说想要他的嘴唇在我嘴上
Uh, can we just cut to the chase?
我们能直接切入正题吗
He's got great lips.
他的嘴唇很性感
No, no, no, no, no. What are we doing here?
不不不  我们在这里干什么
What is this about?
你们有什么目的
Nothing! We just wanted to have a fun night out
没什么  我们就是想跟我们的女儿
with our daughter.
出来放松一下
Yeah! Just think of us as your friends.
是啊  就把我们当做你的朋友
- Yeah! - I don't have 45-year-old friends.
-是啊  -我可没有45岁的朋友
Well, you don't have 45-year-old parents yet, either, honey,
你的父母也还没45岁呢  亲爱的
so calm down.
别激动
Haley has no plan for her future whatsoever.
海莉对她的未来毫无规划
She's living in our basement,
她住在我们的地下室里
taking community-college classes, and, well, meandering.
在社区大学上课  整天混日子
So we're gonna take her out. We'll have some fun.
所以我们打算带她出去  放松一下
And then gently ease her
让她放松警惕
into a friendly conversationabout her future.
跟我们友好地聊聊她的未来
As opposed to the approach that we've taken in the past.
跟我们过去采取的方式截然不同
Is this what you're gonna do with your life --
你打算以后就干这个吗
Sleep late and take a selfie?!
睡懒觉  然后自拍
Why are you always criticizing me?!
你为什么总是批评我
Is this really how you want to start the day?!
你想这样开始新的一天吗
My day started 5 hours ago.
我的一天五小时前就开始了
I am under a lot of pressure!
我的压力很大
How?! How?! You take three classes a week,
怎么大  如何大  你一周只有三节课
and you miss half of them!
还逃了一半
The parking is tricky!
车很难停
Morning, sunshine. I saved you some lunch.
早上好  宝贝  我给你留了些午餐
I get it, okay?! I'm lazy! God!
我知道了  好吗  我是很懒  天呐
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译 禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
■
You know what drives me crazy?
你知道我最烦什么吗
Getting these customer-satisfaction calls during dinner.
晚餐期间接到询问客户满意度的电话
They change the oil on your car,
他们给车换了油而已
they want a love letter!
却期待着我写感谢信
I know. I'm waiting for a call from my doctor's office --
没错  我还在等我的医生打来电话
"Please rate your prostate exam.
"请评价您的前列腺检查
Would you say you were satisfied?"
您满意吗"
I hope you weren't.
我希望你没有
"I hope you weren't."
"我希望你没有"
That's a good one, Gloria!
这太好笑了  歌洛莉亚
Do you know how hard it is
你知道用第二语言
to be funny in a second language, Jay?
幽默一下有多困难吗  杰
Esta Hermosa Dama es muy buena.
这位美丽的小姐真不错
Ay, Darlene, you're learning Spanish?
达琳  你在学西班牙语吗
Yes, Shorty and I have been taking classes.
是啊  小短和我开始上课了
- We're getting good. - Oh, yeah.
-我们越说越好了  -当然
I es maravilloso!
太棒了
You said "That's wonderful," right?
你说的是"太棒了"  对吗
My Italian helps me.
我的意大利语功底帮了我
Why the sudden interest in Spanish?
为什么突然对西语感兴趣
Well, actually, there's something we have to tell you,
其实我们有件事想告诉你们
you know? All right. How's this? We're-
好吧  你们看如何  我们
- We're moving to Costa Rica! - Yeah!
-我们要搬去哥斯达黎加啦  -是的
- What?! - When?
-什么  -什么时候
In a couple of weeks. The cost of living is so low down there,
再过几周  那里的生活成本很低
you know? We found this beautiful place on the water.
我们在海边找了个美丽的地方
It's got its own private beach.
还有自己的私人沙滩
Bathing suits are optional.
泳衣可穿可不穿
But encouraged.
但还是鼓励穿上
Ay, I'm going to miss you guys.
我会想你们的
Don't worry about it. I give it three months, tops.
别担心  我赌他们最多能坚持三个月
You hate the beach. And you know how humid it is down there?
你讨厌沙滩  你知道那里有多潮湿吗
I love the steam room at the club.
我爱俱乐部的蒸汽房
It's the same thing, except I don't have to see you
都一样的  除了我再也不用看着你
sitting there like a pile of melted ice cream.
像一滩化了的冰淇淋一样摊在那里
'cause you're Tom Selleck in a towel.
而你披着毛巾就像汤姆・塞立克
I'm just ready for an adventure.
我已经准备好冒险了
I want to try something new.
我想尝试些新事物
Stick around here. Pick up a check every now and then.
待在这里  偶尔交个帐单
Why do you always have to be so negative?
你为什么总是这么消极
I think it's great.
我就觉得很好
No, you're right. I'm sorry.
不  你说得对  我很抱歉
I'm surprised, that's all.
我就是有点吃惊  仅此而已
Let's toast this amazing new chapter of your lives.
我们来为你们美好的生活新篇章干一杯吧
To mosquitoes the size of your fist.
敬拳头大小的蚊子
This is why all your friends move away.
难怪你的朋友们一个个都搬走了
To us, alone at last.
敬我们  终于有独处时间了
We both look very handsome tonight.
我们两个今晚看起来都很帅
You know, if you -- if you'd just said
如果  如果你只说
that I looked handsome, I would have said, "So do you."
我看起来很帅  我就会说  你也是
I couldn't take that chance.
我不敢冒险
I wanted to get off on the right foot.
我想有个良好的开端
Mitchell and I desperately need
米奇尔和我急需一个
a romantic night out to reconnect.
浪漫的夜晚来重燃激情
Yeah. I don't --
是啊  我不
I don't know if it's the stress of planning a wedding,
我不知道是不是因为筹划婚礼压力太大
but we've been a little tense with each other lately, huh?
但我们最近的关系有点紧张
Even our friend J'marcus said how bitchy we've been.
连我们的朋友马库斯都说我们最近很暴躁
What -- when did he say that?
什么  他什么时候说过这话
Oh, at Pepper's party
在胡娇的派对上
that night you wore those pants that don't fit you anymore.
那晚你穿了那条不太合适的裤子
Oh, right. And you brought that bad wine that everybody hated.
没错  而你带了一瓶大家都讨厌的酒
- See? We really need this. - We really do.
-瞧  我们真的很需要  -真心的
Oh, you know, uh, Pepper said
那天胡娇说
that for our cake tasting,
为了我们的蛋糕试吃
we needed to have --
我们得...
Remember our rules -- no wedding talk, no Lily talk.
我们说好的  不谈婚礼  不谈莉莉
I'm sorry. No, you're right.
抱歉  好吧  你是对的
So, just gonna...
那么我们聊聊...
Should we hear the specials again?
我们再听一遍招牌菜怎么样
We can't ask him a third time.
不能再让他重复第三遍了
You know what I might try when I'm down there?
你知道我搬过去以后会做什么吗
Surfing.
冲浪
So it's gonna be a closed casket.
那看来你的遗体无法供亲友瞻仰了[死得很惨]
My turn.
该我了
What are you talking about? I just sunk the 3 ball.
你在说什么  我刚刚打进了3号球
Then you moved the cue ball with your stick
然后你的杆子碰到了白色球
while you were telling me how you were gonna move away
就在你跟我讲要从南加州搬走
from Southern California to try surfing.
去学冲浪的时候
I didn't touch the cue ball.
我没碰白色球
Yeah, I know. But you did.
是啊我知道  但你就是碰了
You're calling me a cheater? You?
你说我是骗子吗  你
The guy on the golf course who can't seem to count higher than 5?
一个打高尔夫最多数到5杆的家伙
Maybe I can't keep track of my shots
我忘记杆数是因为
because somebody won't stop talking.
我身边总有个家伙喋喋不休
It is in my nature to comment on
那是因为我天生就爱
the bizarre and unusual things I see in the world,
对看到的奇闻异事发表评论
like that convulsion you call a golf swing.
比如你总是将胡乱一击称为挥杆
You know what? I'm done here.
你猜怎么着  我不打了
No, I've done.
是我不打了
I will not have my integrity questioned here.
我不能站在这里接受你对我人品的质疑
I was a Marine.
我参加过海军
I served with guys who died.
一同服役的伙伴有些都为国捐躯了
Of old age!
那是老死的
You never left the states!
你连国门都没出过
Are you saying I didn't serve my country?
你是说我没为国家效力吗
Which one, America or Costa Rica?
哪个国家  美国还是哥斯达黎加
What's with you and Costa Rica?!
你干嘛老跟哥斯达黎加过不去
It's a terrible idea!
因为那是个糟糕的主意
You get into things without thinking,
你总是头脑发热冲动做决定
and you need to be rescued,
你需要被当头棒喝
like that time you bought that car
就像上次你买的那辆车
that was supposed to turn into a boat!
说什么可以变成一条船
- Yeah? - It turned into a reef!
-怎么了  -结果变成沉船
That's 'cause you left your door cracked open!
那是因为你手贱没关车门
Yes, it was my fault.
是啊  又变成我的责任了
Mark my words --
记住我的话
Costa Rica is another amphibicar
哥斯达黎加就是下一个
at the bottom of a lake.
沉在湖底的水下汽车
Only this time, I won't be bailing you out!
只不过这一次  我不会再捞你起来了
Who asked you?!
谁要你捞了
Darlene, we're going!
达琳  我们走
Wha-- wha-- what do you mean, we're going?
怎么了  为什么要走
Gracias, Gloria.
谢谢款待  歌洛莉亚
That was a lovely dinner.
晚餐很棒
And you are an incredible woman for putting up with this gringo!
你能忍受得了这个家伙实在太伟大了
- Come on! - What happened?
-快点  -怎么回事
Good luck in Costa Rica!
祝你在哥斯达黎加有好运
- Aw, thanks, Jay. - He didn't mean it!
-谢谢你  杰  -他在说反话
I know! I'm trying to defuse the tension.
我知道  我只是想缓和下气氛
- Here we go, guys. - Oh, yeah!
-上酒了  -太棒了
- Three more Mojitos. - Yum!
-再来三杯莫吉托  -好喝极了
Aren't these yum?
是不是美味到爆啊
I didn't even drink the first one.
我第一杯都没碰过
Are you sure? 'cause I don't think it drank itself.
你确定吗  它总不会平白无故消失了吧
No, it did not.
是啊  确实不是
Look, I have no problem drinking.
我喝酒一点问题都没有
I can literally do it standing on my head.
说真的姐倒立着都能喝酒
But, "A," not with my parents,
但是  首先  我不跟爸妈一起喝
and plus, also, I needed to stay sharp,
其次  我得保持清醒
because they were obviously up to something,
因为他们显然醉翁之意不在酒
and I was in no mood.
而且我也没心情喝酒
I barely got 10 hours of sleep last night.
昨晚我才睡了不到10个小时
So, I'll go get you guys some more water,
我给你们再拿点水
and your food should be out in just a few minutes.
主菜应该马上就来了
Thanks so much, pal. We appreciate it.
谢谢你伙计  你的服务很周到
He seems like a real go-getter, huh?
他看上去真是积极进取啊  对吧
Oh, 'cause he goes and gets things?
因为他总是"进"厨房"取"东西吗
I wonder what he wants to do with his life.
我想知道他对人生有什么规划
I wonder that about people all the time.
我总是很好奇别人的人生规划
I think that's very common,
我觉得这很正常
to wonder about other people's aspirations.
想知道其他人的志向
I do it all the time.
我总是这样
- Yeah, you do. - Yeah. Here we go.
-是  你是这样  -好了  水来了
Hey, Brian, you're a young guy.
布莱恩  作为一个年轻人
Wha-- wha-- what do you want to do after this? What's your plan?
你在这之后想做点什么  有什么规划吗
Uh, to be perfectly honest,
说实话
I'm probably gonna go home, watch a movie, and get high.
我大概会回家  看看电影  再磕点药
You guys looking for something to do?
你们在考虑饭后的活动吗
No. No. No.
不  不  不
Oh. I mean, I think I got extra.
我还有点存货
No, no, that's --
不用了  你真是...
I-I think he meant your plan for your life,
他是在问你对人生的规划
not -- not just tonight.
不是指今天晚上
Oh. I want to be a screenwriter.
我想当编剧
- Ambitious. - And -- and so interesting.
-很有理想  -真有意思
Isn't that interesting, Haley?
是不是啊  海莉
- Sure. - You should tell him what you're doing.
-当然了  -你应该跟他说说你的事
Oh, you mean after we all go get high with Brian?
你是说在我们一起跟布莱恩嗑完药之后吗
That's not happening.
那是不可能的
I'm sorry. I meant that --
很抱歉拒绝你  我是说
No, I know what you meant.
我知道你们的意思
Hey, Brian, could you give us a second?
布莱恩  你可以回避一下吗
Uh, ye-- sure.
好  当然
So this is what this whole night's about --
这就是你们今天带我来的原因
the drinks, the pretending to be my friend?
鸡尾酒  假装是我朋友  都是幌子
We are your friend.
我们确实是你的朋友
Honey, we care about you.
亲爱的  我们很关心你
And we want to make sure that you -- you've got a plan,
我们想确定你有自己的人生规划
'cause it seems like you're meandering.
因为看上去你在混日子
No. Sweetie, don't just start texting
别这样  亲爱的  不要每次谈到
because you don't like the conversation.
你不喜欢的话题就开始玩手机
- Here. - What is this?
-看  -这是什么
That's a blog that I've been doing.
这是我一直在写的博客
I'm really liking my photography,
我真的很喜欢我拍的照片
and people always say that they like the way that I dress,
别人也总说他们喜欢我的穿衣风格
so I've been posting pictures of my outfits on this site.
所以我就在这个网站上传我的穿着搭配
I know it's not a huge money-maker right now,
我知道现在还赚不了多少钱
but I do get money whenever someone clicks on a link
但每当有人点击链接  买我穿的衣服时
and buys something that I wore.
我就会有收入
I'm gonna take a business class next semester,
下学期我会去上商务课
which I'm hoping will help me turn all of this
希望能帮助我通过现在做的事
into becoming a stylist.
成为一个造型师
I have 1,200 followers.
我已经有1200个粉丝了
Most are women who want to know what to wear.
多数是想知道怎样穿衣搭配的女人
Some are men who want to know what I'm wearing,
还有一些想知道我穿什么的男人
But, you know, I'm trying to figure a way
不过我已经在想办法
to block all of the pervs.
屏蔽那些变态了
So, yeah. I guess that is my plan.
所以  这就是我的规划
It's amazing.
真是太棒了
We are so proud of you.
我们真为你骄傲
Don't even, guys. You always assume the worst of me.
省省吧  你们总是用恶意揣测我
Honey --
亲爱的
No, you guys sit here
你们两个坐在那儿
acting like we're drinking buddies, judging me,
假装是我的朋友  却对我评头论足
when I have a better handle on my future
事实是我对未来的规划比你们两个
than either one of you did at my age.
在我这么大时能做到的都要好
You? You wanted to be a magician.
你曾经想做个魔术师
And you were changing your major every three minutes,
而你呢  三分钟就换一次专业
according to grandpa --
这是外公告诉我的
who, by the way,
顺便说一句
has been drinking with me for years
我和外公一起喝酒好多年了
because he loves me,
因为他爱我
and he thinks I say funny things when I'm buzzed.
而且觉得我喝高了的时候说话很风趣
Well, apparently, the situation in Syria is worsening.
很显然  叙利亚局势日趋紧张
I know.
是啊
In fact, now U.N. evidence suggests that Assad was --
现在联合国有证据显示阿萨德
Are you reading this off your phone?
你是在照着手机念么
What?!
什么
You're --
你在
No! No! What --
不是  没有
- I was just making sure my facts were straight... - Cam.
-我只是在确认没有记错细节  -小卡
...before I started a spirited conversation of current events.
以便我对当今局势高谈阔论
Yeah.
好吧
What else does it say?
还说什么了
Thank you.
谢谢
Sorry. Is that the tuna tartare?
不好意思  那是金枪鱼鞑靼吗
Yes, and it is delicious.
是啊  很好吃
Oh, I should've ordered it.
我应该点那个的
Would you like a taste?
想尝一口吗
Oh, no. But thank you. That's very sweet.
不用了  但是谢谢  你人真好
She really means it. Uh, Katie loves sharing food.
她是认真的  卡蒂喜欢跟别人分享食物
Me, too. You know, I think
我也是  我觉得
it's growing up in a big family,
在大家庭里长大都会这样
'cause everything at suppertime on the table
因为晚餐桌上的所有东西
was up for grabs.
都是给大家一起吃的
We didn't say grace.
我们不做饭前祷告
We said, "On your marks, get set, go."
我们会说  各就各位  预备  开吃
You sound exactly like my dad.
你的语气跟我爸完全一样
He was from this really big family in Missouri, and --
他出生在密苏里一个很大的家庭里
Shut up!
不是吧
I'm a Missouri farm boy, myself!
我自己就是个密苏里的乡下孩子
- Stop! - Oh, my gosh! I'm Cam.
-不是吧  -天啊  我叫小卡
Well, right pleased to meet you, Cam.
很高兴认识你  小卡
This is Brandon.
这是布兰登
Hi. She doesn't really talk like that.
你好  她平常不这样说话的
Oh, well, he slips in and out of his accent
他时不时也会有口音
like Kate Winslet in "Titanic."
就像《泰坦尼克号》里的凯特・温丝莱特
- Uh, I'm Mitchell, by the way. - Hi.
-我叫米奇尔  -你好
- Hi. - What -- what's yours, Brandon?
-你好  -你点了什么  布兰登
It looks delicious, too.
看起来也很好吃
It's the truffle parmesan gnocchi.
这是马铃薯干酪松露
Do you know what, though? If you want a bite of that,
但是你知道吗  如果你想尝一口那个
you're barking up the wrong tree.
你就找错人了
'cause that dish is in a strict no-share zone.
因为那是一个严格的不分享区
I just --
我只是
I don't like people eating off my plate.
不喜欢别人从我的盘子里吃东西
Yeah, because you're not an animal. I'm the same way.
因为我们不是动物  我也一样
Oh, my gosh! You're exactly us!
天啊  我们完全一样
No, you guys are more interesting,
不  你们要更有趣
'cause you have the whole gay thing.
因为你们基情四射
Katie, you don't know if they're gay.
卡蒂  你都不知道他们是不是
Okay, that's adorable.
你真可爱
Yeah, it was -- it was a pretty safe bet.
是啊  我们的关系很明显
Okay. I'm running to the powder room.
我要去下洗手间
Cam, please try the tartare,
小卡  尝尝这个
because whatever you order, I want a taste.
一会儿不管你点了什么  我也要尝尝
Okay. Well, don't you dillydally,
没问题  不过你要快点回来
because I ain't exactly slow once I tie on the ol' feed bag!
因为我一挂上饲料袋就慢不下来
Calm down, honey boo boo.
别激动  亲爱的
- She's so cute! - Very adorable.
-她真可爱  -超级可爱
So, Brandon, what do you do for a living? Are you --
布兰登  你是做什么工作的
Look, guys. I-I hate to be blunt,
听我说  伙计们  我不想这么没礼貌
but could you please give us some space?
但是你们能不能给我们一点空间
Not a problem.
没问题
Look, no -- no, it's --
不  不是
I mean, you guys are great. But I'm gonna...
你们人很好  只是我
propose to Katie tonight.
我今晚要向卡蒂求婚
And I'm kind of feeling -- yeah.
而我觉现在有点...
What?! Here?!
什么  在这吗
Oh, my god! That's amazing!
天啊  这太棒了
We just got engaged a few months ago.
我们几个月前刚刚订婚
Great.
太好了
Yeah, so we will definitely give you your privacy.
所以我们一定会尊重你们的隐私
- Congratulations. - Absolutely.
-恭喜你  -是啊
Yeah. Good luck.
祝你好运
You know what? If you wanted,
这样吧  如果你想的话
I could pretend like I'm texting,
我可以假装在发短信
and I could video the whole thing on my phone.
然后用手机把整个过程录下来
That way, you'd have it forever.
这样你就能留作纪念了
Really? I mean, that -- yeah.
真的吗  好啊
- That would be awesome. - A-are you sure?
-那太好了  -你确定吗
He gets very, uh, well, excited.
他很容易过于激动
And he might give it away.
有可能会漏出马脚
Mitchell, um, I think I know Katie well enough
米奇尔  我觉得凭我对卡蒂的了解
to tell if she's getting suspicious.
我能看出她有没有起疑心
- Cam?! - She said I could.
-小卡  -她说过我可以尝尝的
The hell's the corkscrew?
见鬼的开瓶器去哪儿了
Do you want to talk about it?
你想谈谈吗
There's nothing to talk about!
没什么可谈的
Shorty does dumb things all the time.
小短总是做傻事
You mark my words -- in three months,
我打赌  不出三个月
he'll be back here needing money.
他就会花光钱滚回来了
Maybe this is not about Shorty coming back.
也许你不高兴不是因为小短会滚回来
Maybe this is about Shorty not coming back.
而是因为小短可能不会回来了
Manny.
曼尼
What she's saying is, deep down,
她的意思是  在你内心深处
you're afraid Shorty's going to love Costa Rica,
害怕小短会爱上哥斯达黎加
and you'll lose your best friend forever.
你就永远失去自己最好的朋友了
That's what you do.
你一直都是这样
You push people away, so when they leave,
你故意疏远别人  这样他们离开时
it doesn't hurt that much.
你就不会那么难受
I don't get it. You're the greatest generation,
我搞不明白  你们这代人那么伟大
but why can't you feel?
怎么就没有情感呢
Why can't you spend your teen years
你怎么不能像其他青春期少年
locked in your bedroom like a normal kid?
整天呆在房间不出来呢
See? Now he's doing it to me.
看吧  他现在在疏远我了
Uh, you have to face it, Jay.
杰  这是你必须面对的
One day, I'll be moving out of this house.
我终有一天会搬出去
Can I get that in writing?
你可以写个保证吗
'cause I just can't shake this image of a 30-year-old you
我脑海里现在都是30岁的你
eating my food and cuddling with my wife.
吃着我的食物  还黏着我老婆
Boys should never stop cuddling their mothers.
男孩子永远都该黏他们的妈妈
I'm gonna have nightmares!
我会做噩梦的
You pretend to be so tough.
你假装很强硬
But you know what I think?
可你知道我怎么想吗
I think that deep down,
我觉得事实上
you're the most sensitive person in this house.
你才是这屋子里感情最细腻的人
See?
看吧
You did it again.
又开始了
I say something that strikes a nerve,
一说到这种敏感的话题
and immediately, you cannot handle it.
你就受不了了
That's why you "Pbht" in my face!
所以你才这样逃避话题
We just found the one thing you can't make sexy.
终于发现一个你不那么可爱的地方了
There it is again.
又来了
I need a drink.
我需要喝一杯
Jay, you have to make this right with Shorty.
杰  你得跟小短说清楚
You have to tell him how you feel!
告诉他你的真实感受
He has been a great compadre with you for many years.
他可是你那么多年的老朋友
Besides, who else is going to laugh at your jokes?
除了他还有谁给你的笑话捧场
Lots of people laugh at my jokes.
大把人欣赏我的笑话
Name one person that doesn't work for you.
除了你的员工以外还有别人吗
Hey, you know what? Why don't you two just go cuddle?
要不你们两个还是一边温存去吧
Okay, here she comes.
她来了
Stay calm.
淡定
- You're gonna spoil it. - You stay calm.
-你会露馅的  -你才要淡定
Ooh, that looks good. What is it?
看起来真不错  这是什么
Um, uh, this is the grilled calamari.
这个是烤鱿鱼圈
It's scrumptious. Would you care for a ring?
很美味的  你要不要来一"环"
I -- um, I mean, dig in there, girlfriend!
我是说你要不要尝一下  亲
Oh, no, that's okay. Thank you.
不用了  谢谢
This looks so delicious.
看起来超美味
Yeah, mine's delicious, too.
我的也很美味
Katie...
卡蒂
You look so beautiful tonight.
你今晚真美
You know, I-I've never met anyone like you,
要知道我从来没遇到过像你这么好的人
and I know that I never will. And I...
我也知道不可能再遇到了
I love you so much.
我好爱你
Will you make me the happiest man on earth
你能让我变成世界上最幸福的男人吗
- and be my bride? - What?!
-嫁给我  -什么
Oh, my god!
我的天啊
- No! - No?
-不行  -不行吗
No!
不行
Sorry.
对不起
Did you know that this place used to be a bank?
你知道这里以前是个银行吗
Was it, really?
真的哦
I just -- I don't want to be married, Brandon.
我只是  我不想结婚  布兰登
We'll end up like one of those couples
我们会变得跟那些
that just sits there with nothing to talk about
相对无言的夫妻一样
until we glom on to other people.
直到移情别恋
I can't believe this. You -- you don't love me?
我简直不敢相信  你  你不爱我吗
- NO! - NO?
-不  -不爱吗
- I'm sor... - NO!
-对不起  -不
I need some air.
我需要透透气
So, Syria, any updates?
叙利亚那边有什么新情况
- No, nothing yet. - Nothing.
-还没什么  -没有啊
Do you remember how cute she was when she was little
你还记得她小时候发不出"p"这个音
- and she couldn't say her P's?  - "BAKE A-TATOES."
-有多可爱吗  -烤"堵"豆
"Bake a-tatoes" and "Attlesauce".
烤"堵"豆  还有"饼"果酱
"Attlesauce"!
"饼"果酱
"Can I have attlesauce?"
能给我点"饼"果酱吗
First of all, you're screaming.
首先  你有点高了
Can we just get the check, please?
我们可以买单了吗  拜托
Could you please not be mad at us anymore?
你可以不要生我们的气了吗
We are very sorry that you felt manipulated.
我们很抱歉让你有被摆布的感觉
You know what I'm pretty sure is ironic?
你们知道我觉得最讽刺的是什么吗
You guys spend all this time worrying
你们花那么多时间担心
about what I'm going to do,
我将来要做什么
and maybe you should start thinking
但也许你们应该开始思考一下
about what you're going to do.
你们要做什么了
What are you talking about?
这是什么意思
Well, what are you gonna do when we're gone?
我们都离开家以后你们打算做什么
What's your plan?
有什么计划
- Uh, to be fine. - Yeah.
-我们会好好的  -是啊
- 'cause we're fine. - Totally.
-因为我们很好啊  -特别好
You guys are gone.
你们都走了
We get an R.V. Bam!
我们就买辆休旅车
Me, mama...
我  你妈妈
and our dog, Merlin, hit the open road.
外加一条狗  默林  踏上旅程
No. I am not spending my golden years
不  我可不要把我的晚年
driving around an R.V. park,
浪费在一个个房车公园里
looking for a place to plug my house in.
整日寻找地方安营扎寨
No. I am gonna go see the world.
不  我要去周游世界
Where do you wanna go?
那你想去哪里
I don't know, Phil. India. Africa.
我不知道  菲尔  印度  非洲
Diarrhea. Diarrhea.
痢疾  会得痢疾
Wow. It sounds like you guys really need to start thinking
看起来你们真的要开始规划一下
about your future.
你们的未来了
Are you just gonna put Merlin in a kennel when we're gone?
我们走后你要让默林住在狗舍吗
Okay, Phil, Merlin doesn't exist.
菲尔  默林根本不存在
And why do you want to get a dog to take care of
孩子们走后你为何要
so soon after the kids leave?
急于找只狗来养呢
Well, I'm gonna need someone to love me, Claire.
因为我需要有人疼爱  克莱尔
And in the meantime, mom,
与此同时  妈妈
grandpa wants you to take over the business, but...
外公想让你接管公司  但是
Do you want that?
那是你想要的吗
I-I guess I hadn't thought this far into the future.
这么久远的事情我还没想过
And, dad, are you just gonna keep selling houses?
爸爸  你要一直以卖房子为生吗
I mean, I don't want to blow your mind here,
我不是想要动摇你的心思
but you could still be a magician.
但你还是可以成为一个魔术师啊
I could.
我可以
He couldn't.
他不行
Really?
真的吗
This salt shaker behind your head says different.
你身后的这个盐罐可不是这么说的
Oh, Phil, you're getting salt all over me.
菲尔  你把盐弄到我身上了
I feel like a Margarita.
我要变成玛格丽特了[想要一杯]
- You got it! - No, no, no, no, no, no!
-马上来  -不  不  不  不
Just the check, please.
结账吧  麻烦了
Okay.
好的
Thank you so much.
非常感谢你
- Thanks, buddy. - Yeah.
-谢了  兄弟  -多谢
Oh, no. I left my wallet in the other coat.
糟了  我的钱包在另一件外套里
I did not bring my purse.
我没带包包
It's fine, guys. I got this.
没事  我来吧
- Honey, thank you. - Oh, thank you, sweetie.
-谢谢你宝贝  -谢谢你  亲爱的
- I should probably drive, too, huh? - Probably.
-等下看来也要我来开车了吧  -是啊
- I gue-- yeah. - Yeah.
-我觉得  也是  -是啊
Why don't you guys have the valet pull the car up
不如我留在这里结账  你们去叫门童
while I pay the check?
把车取来
That we can do.
这倒是可以
Uh, you guys, it's that way.
伙计们  那边
- Mm-hmm. - It is.
-是吧  -是啊
Y-you know, for the record, we do have a lot to talk about.
顺便说一下  我们其实有很多可聊的
Yeah, we just took a couple of topics off the table
今天只是把有些话题先放一放
because we wanted to have a romantic date night.
因为我们今晚想来一次浪漫的约会
And it probably put too much pressure on it to be special,
也许我们太想让今晚特别一点了
but the truth is, every day I spend with this man is special.
事实上我和他在一起的每一天都很特别
Oh, Cam!
小卡
Oh, no, I'm the lucky one.
不  我才是幸运的那个人
There we are.
我们都是
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I guess I just panicked when Brandon asked me.
我想刚才布兰登求婚时我只是慌乱了
I mean, we're so different. And I know it seems petty,
我们很不一样  我知道这看来
but it speaks to something bigger.
很矫情  但其实不然
I don't know if I can spend the rest of my life
我不知道我能否与一个
with the kind of guy who won't let me eat off his plate.
不让我碰他食物的人共度余生
Trust me -- it can be done.
相信我  那不是问题
And I should not make such a big deal about that.
我也不应该太在乎这件事
I promise I'll try and do better.
我保证会努力调整的
No, you're right. You don't like it,
不  你说得对  你不喜欢我那样
and I should respect that more.
我就应该尊重你的喜好
Are you guys married?
你们结婚了吗
Oh, this May.
今年五月结
- But, basically, we've been married for years. - Yeah.
-但我们算是结婚很多年了  -是的
I-I mean, is Cam everything that I dreamed of?
小卡难道就是我心中的完美人选吗
Tread lightly, counselor.
谨言慎行  律师
Yes. Yes, he is.
是的  他就是
Because through all the compromises
因为尽管经历了种种妥协
and negotiations and arguments
协商与争执
and sometimes even boredom,
甚至是厌倦情绪
I cannot picture my life without him.
我无法想象没有他的生活
That's very sweet.
说得真好
I would've scooted past the boredom, but...
但要是我就不会说厌倦  不过
At the end of the day, Katie, you have to ask yourself,
说到最后  卡蒂  你必须问问你自己
can you imagine your life without this person?
你能想象没有这个人的生活吗
Hey. All right, look.
好了
I, uh, paid the check, okay? Let's just go.
我买完单了  我们走吧
Brandon, can you just please sit?
布兰登  你能先坐下吗
I've been talking to the guys here,
我一直在和他们两个聊
and they really opened my eyes.
他们真的让我想了很多
They did?
真的吗
Yes.
是的
I've been trying to picture my life without you, and...
我尝试着想象没有你的生活
You know what?
你知道吗
I can.
我能接受
We didn't tell her that.
我们可没那么说
I didn't say that.
我没那么说
No, I want what you guys have, okay?
不  我想和你们一样  懂吗
I'm sorry, Brandon.
抱歉  布兰登
I am so sorry, but we both deserve that.
对不起  但我们都该有那样的感情
I've never been so sure of anything.
我从未如此确定过
You know what? I'm just...
好了  我还是
gonna go get a cab, okay?
打车回去好了
Goodbye.
再见
And thank you.
谢谢
- Don't-- don't thank us! - We didn't do anything,
-别  别谢我们  -我们什么都没做
So... we didn't, honestly.
我们真的没有
This is the worst night of my life.
这真是我人生最悲剧的一晚
I'm sorry.
抱歉
But, I mean, um, a-at least now it's over.
但是好在一切都结束了
You can... start to move on.
你可以开始新生活了
I've been trying to picture my life without you.
我尝试着想象没有你的生活
And you know what?
你知道吗
- S-stupid phone. - I can.
-傻缺手机  -我能接受
It's a... devil phone.
这手机着魔了
When Mitchell was born, he was a month premature.
米奇尔出生时  早产了一个月
So it was touch and go there for a while.
当时事态很紧急
It's 2 a.m.
是凌晨两点
I walk out into the hospital waiting room to get some air,
我走进医院的等候室想喘口气
and there's Shorty.
小短也在
He'd been sitting there for six hours
他在那坐了六个小时了
and refused to leave for the next two days.
还坚持要继续再呆两天
That's where we got Mitchell's middle name.
米奇尔的中间名就是这么来的
Not Shorty --
不是叫小短
Vincent.
是文森特
"M.V.P."
M.V.P[最有价值球员]
We were a little premature on that one, too.
这点上我们也有些不成熟
Gloria, I'm going for a drive!
歌洛莉亚  我要开车出去了
Say hi to Shorty for me!
替我向小短问好
I'm not talking to you!
没跟你说话
I was just coming to see you.
我正要去找你
Um, I left my jacket.
我把外套落在这里了
Oh! There it is! Come on in.
在这呢  进来吧
Uh, Shorty, you know that stuff I said, uh --
小短  你知道我说的那些话
- Yeah, I get it. - We're good, huh?
-我懂  -我们没事吧
Under the bridge.
没事
All right. I'll see you.
好的  回头见
Shorty, wait.
小短  等等
I need to say something to you.
我有话想跟你说
Yeah.
说吧
I want to thank you...
我想说谢谢你
for all the great times we've had.
感谢我们一同经历的好时光
Yeah. We, um...
是啊  我们
- We had a lot of laughs. - Yeah.
-我们有过很多快乐时光  -是啊
And you should know that, uh...
你应该知道
you're my best friend.
你是我最好的朋友
You know?
知道吗
Probably the best friend I'm ever gonna have.
也许是我一生中最好的朋友
Jay, I mean... what are you doing to me?
杰  你这是干什么
This is hard for me. I'm just...
这对我有点难  我只是
I'm just trying to tell you how I feel.
我只是想告诉你我的感受
Well, I'm gonna tell you how I feel.
那我也告诉你我的感受
I admire the hell out of you, Jay.
我真崇拜你  杰
I always tell Darlene, "That's a real guy."
我总跟达琳说  "这是个真男人"
Self-made, stand-up,
自立  敢说敢干
the kind of guy you want to be in a foxhole with.
是那种你愿意和他在同一战壕奋斗的人
Well, I'm not all that.
我没那么好
Well, it's not like I've been in a foxhole.
我也没下过战壕
I'm gonna miss you, Vincent.
我会想你的  文森特
I'm gonna miss you, too.
我也会想你的
I love you.
我爱你
I love you, too, Jay bird.
我也爱你  小杰杰
I really, really do.
真的非常爱
You call me, okay?
给我打电话  好吗
Every day.
每天都打
Every damn day.
每一天
If I'm being honest,
说实话
this is a little girlier than I thought.
我没想到场面会这么娘
Two years.
两年
How could she just walk away?
她怎么就这么走了
- You know what? She did you a favor. - Absolutely.
-知道吗  她这是帮了你  -绝对的
- You can do so much better. - Oh, my god. Insanely better.
-你能找到更好的  -好上百倍的
No, he's not kidding. Brandon, you are seriously gorge!
他没开玩笑  布兰登  你这么帅
If you ask me, she got the better end of the deal.
要我说  她和你在一起绝对是占便宜了
You really think so?
你们真这么觉得吗
- Yes! Yes! - Yes!
-是啊是啊  -是啊
And her whole fake blond thing? I don't know.
还有她那头假金发  我不确定
- It was kind of trampy. - And truth be told,
-有点不太正经  -而且说实话
she didn't seem that bright.
她看起来不是很阳光
And is she older than you?
她是不是比你大
- Because she looked significantly older than you. - Trust us.
-她看起来比你大多了  -相信我们
This is the best thing that's ever happened to you.
这是发生在你身上的最好的事了
Best thing that's ever happened to you.
这辈子发生的最好的事
Oh! Thank god you're still here!
谢天谢地  你还在
I was on my way home, and all of a sudden, I started crying.
刚刚在回家的路上  突然我就哭了
And I realized I was just scared.
我意识到我刚刚只是被吓到了
And I love you. And I'm so, so sorry.
我爱你  我真的很抱歉
And, yes, Brandon, if you'll still have me,
我愿意  布兰登  如果你还愿意娶我
Yes, I will marry you!
我愿意  我要嫁给你
- So nice meeting you. - Okay.
-认识你们很高兴  -走吧